Guide to the Warren Jay Vinton papers, 1932-1969
Vinton, Warren Jay papers, 1932-1969
- Series XIV. Warren Jay Vinton Speeches and Publications, 1936-1964, arranged by year
  - Speeches and Publications, 1964- "The President and Public Housing- Recollections of his original show in interest in 1938," article in Journal of Housing, #1, 1964 and correspondence (Box 16)
- Series XV. Articles
  - "The Annual Contributions Contract in Theory and Practices 10/10/51"- Speech at NAHO Annual Conference, 1951 (Box 16)
  - "The Mutual Responsibilities of Local and Federal Authorities for the Public Housing Program, Nov. 16, 1949"- speech at NAHO conference, Boston (MC) (Box 16)
  - "The Place of Low-Rent Housing Program in Municipal Government, Dec. 1, 1949"- Speech at American Municiapl Association Conference (Box 16)
  - "Progress in Financing Low-Rent Housing during Fiscal Year 1954"-Paper (Box 16)
  - "Progress in the Financing of Low-Rent Public Housing during 1955 7/16/56"- Report and review in The Bond Buyer, 1956 (Box 16)
  - "Progress in Financing Public Housing during 1956 (Prepared For HHFA Annual Report, 1956)"- Report and reprint in Daily Bond Buyer, 1957 (Box 16)
  - "Public Housing and the Democratic Process 6/13/50"-Speech at Pacific Southwest Regional Council of National Association of Housing Officials (Box 16)
  - "Public Housing Financing 2/4/55"- Speech before Municipal Forum of New York, 1955 (Box 16)
  - "Recent Developments in the Financing of Low-Rent Public Housing 2/12/53"-Paper and supplement, 1953 (Box 16)
  - "Remarks at Dedication Ceremonies of Flag House Court, Baltimore, MD 2/3/54"-Speech, 1954 (Box 16)
  - "The Role of Public Housing in the Rebuilding of Our Cities Dec. 7, 1949"- Speech at Citizen's Housing and Planning Council of New York (Box 16)
  - "Urban Redevelopment and Public Housing Programs Must Work Together Dec. 1949"-Article in The American City (Box 16)
  - [The Urban Revolution: Challenge to the Next Generation] [folder with no tab]-Speech to and correspondence with Washington Center for Metropolitan Studies and Conference on the Teacher and Metropolis Nov. 29, 1962, 1962-63 (Box 17)
  - "ASPO Speech"- [American Society of Planning Officials]-Speech "Which Way Public Housing" for National Conference of ASPO, correspondence and clipping concerning Vinton's resignation from NHA, 1958 (Box 17)
  - Benjamin Stolberg and Warren J. Vinton, The Economic Consequences of the New Deal, NY: Harcourt and Brace, 1935; letters and statements, Dec. 6, 1934-July 5, 1938 (Box 23)
  - "Economic Consequences of the New Deal"-letters and royalty statements, Dec. 6, 1934-July 5, 1938, congratulations, business (Box 23)
  - The Economic Consequences of the New Deal-"Who Holds the Aces In the New Deal" (1st Draft) "The Deck was Stacked" (2nd draft) "The New Era Behind the New Deal" (3rd draft) "The Middle Classes" (4th draft) (Box 23)
  - Benjamin Stolberg and Warren J. Vinton, The Economic Consequences of the New Deal, chapter The Degradation.. .(MSS, draft of chapter I) (Box 23)
  - The Economic Consequences of the New Deal- draft of Chapter I: "The Degredation of the Open Mind" (Box 23)
  - The Economic Consequences of the New Deal-draft of Chapter II: "The Great Predicament" (Box 23)
  - The Economic Consequences of the New Deal-draft of Chapter III: "Big Ownership" (Box 23)
  - The Economic Consequences of the New Deal-Chapter IV: "The Middle Classes" (Box 23)
  - The Economic Consequences of the New Deal-Chapter V: "The Workers" (Box 23)
  - The Economic Consequences of the New Deal-Chapter VI: "The New Deal Panaceas" (Box 23)
  - The Economic Consequences of the New Deal-Chapter VII: "Stalemate" (Box 23)
  - Benjamin Stolberg and Warren J. Vinton, The Economic Consequences of the New Deal, copies one inscribed "from Ben" the second is an English Edition (Box 23?)
  - Benjamin Stolberg and Warren J. Vinton, The Economic Consequences of the New Deal-reviews (Box 23)
  - Reviews and notices, The Economic Consequences of the New Deal, Jan. 22, 1935-Aug. 1936; clippings, TS Father Coughlin, clippings on incident of Father Coughlin's use of quotes from book without acknowledgement on radio talk, March 3, 1935; charged by Harcourt (Box 23)
- Series XVI. Organizations and Conferences, 1949-1969
  - National Association of Housing Officials-Committee on Personnel Standards; Administrative Personnel for Local Housing Authorities. (Chicago, Ill.: The Association, 1937) 14 pp. (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials-Committee on Physical Standards and Construction. Preliminary report.. .Jan. 12, 1938 (MC); report, March 1939 (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials-Demolition of Sub-Standard Housing, April 1938 (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials-Housing for the United States After the War, May 1944 (Box 25)
  - National Association of House Officials-A Housing Program for the United States. (Chicago, Ill.: The Association, 1934) 22 pp. (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials-A housing program for the U.S.; a report prepared for Chicago, Public Information Service, 1935; Public Information Service pub. 38 (annotated) According to Fr. McDonnell (Wagner House Act) pp. 57, this printed by NAHO in 1935. NAHO and Public Info Service housed in same building (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials- Management Training Institute, June 13-24, 1938. Managing Low-Rent Housing. (Chicago, Ill.: The Association, March 1939) 289 pp. (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials-Planning for Low-Rent Housing. (Chicago, Ill.: The Association, 1938) 51 pp. (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials-Public Housing Surveys. (Chicago, Ill.: The Association, 1934) 20 pp. (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials-State Housing Authority Legislation; a Comparative Summary of State Enabling Laws, 1937 (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials-State Laws for Public Housing. (Chicago, Ill.: The Association, 1934) 18 pp. (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Officials- Summary of 1935 State Housing Laws. Supplement to Housing Officials Year Book 1935. (Chicago: The Association, 1935) 9 pp. (MC) (Box 25)
  - National Association of Housing Redevelopment Officials- Title varies: National Association of Housing Officials to 1953; Newsletters, pamphlets, program resolutions, manuals; (see also Office files, Chief Economis 1937-1949), 1934-1965, 1968 (Box 25)
  - National Housing Conference Inc.- Title varies: National Public Housing Conference; Newsletters, reports, membership lists, legislative proposals, some correspondence; (see also: office files, Chief Economist, 1937-1949), 1943-1964 (Box 25)
  - National Housing Conference, Inc.-Newsletters, reports, membership lists, legislative proposals, some correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box 26)
  - Philadelphia Housing Association-Issues, 1957-1964; Citizens' Guide to Housing and Urban Renewal (Box 25)
  - Washington Housing Association-Minutes of Board Meeting (MC), Nov. 27, 1957-Sept. 29, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Washington Housing Association- Reports, testimony, copies of letters sent by Association, copy of "General Urban Renewal Plan: Preliminary Draft Northwest Urban Renewal Area, District of Columbia: by the National Capital Planning Commission, 1957-1958 (Box 15)
  - Washington Housing Association-Letters to Board members (MC), Jan. 17, 1958-Nov. 16, 1960 (Box 15)
  - Washington Housing Association-Letters to the members #13-43, Oct. 1957-Dec. 1960 (Box 15)
  - Washington Housing Association-Reports, statements, testimony, copies of letters sent by Association, 1959-1960 (Box 15)
  - Conferences-Programs, schedules, correspondence for: American Municipal Association 1949 American Society of Planning Officials, 1958-64 Citizens Conference on Washington Area Metropolitan Problems, 1959; Conference of Housing Agency Officials and National Public Interest Organizations, 1950; National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials, 1955, 1960; National Association of Housing Officials, 1949-1953; National Capital Housing Authority, 1957; National Housing Conference, 1956; National Houisng Policy Conference, 1951 (Box 18)
- Series XVII. Newspaper Clippings, 1935-1966
  - New York City Housing Authority- Newspaper clippings especially on housers' conflict with Mayor La Guardia, 1935-1937 (Box 23)
  - Resettlement Administration- Newspaper clippings on establishment and disbanding of Resettlement Administration, 1935-1937 (Box 23)
  - "United States Housing Authority"-Newspaper clippings on establishment USHA, early public housing projects in Louisville and Syracuse, defense housing, merging of housing agencies, 1935-1941 (Box 23)
  - "Reorganization-Housing"-Newspaper clippings on conflict and merging of agencies of war-time housing, 1941 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings-Miscellaneous newspaper clippings on housing bills, bond financing, obituaries, etc., 1943-1966 (Box 23)